A Guide to Virginia Architectural Drawings
Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library, #5946-g
Virginia Architectural Drawings 1970-1971, n.d.
University of Virginia. Library. Special Collections Dept. Alderman Library University of Virginia Charlottesville, Virginia 22903 USA
5946-g
149 items
James A. Cox
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
The drawings were given to the Library by James A. Cox through K. Edward Lay, both of the School of Architecture, Campbell Hall, the University of Virginia, on August 3, 1990.
Scope and Content
This collection consists of measured architectural drawings, 1970-1971, and undated, 149 items, of seventeen historic Virginia buildings. These drawings were produced for the Historic American Building Survey(HABS) by architectural students of the University of Virginia under the direction of Professor James A. Cox of the School of Architecture. The buildings represented are from Northampton County, Essex County, Rockbridge County, Accomack County, Augusta County, Lexington, Strasburg, and Richmond.
Container List
- Alexander-Withrow House, Lexington, Virginia, drawn by Arthur Crook, Daniel Donovan& Gregory Lukmire, 1 complete set (6 sheets) and 1 incomplete set (5 sheets), 1970 (Box Folder 1)
- Glebe House, Tappahannock, Essex County, Virginia, drawn by David Bell, George Candler, & William Daggett, Jr., 1 complete set (6 sheets), 1971 (Box Folder 1)
- Harmony Hall, Strasburg, Virginia, drawn by Arthur Crook, Daniel Donovan & Gregory Lukmire, 1 complete set (7 sheets) and 1 incomplete set (4 sheets), 1970 (Box Folder 1)
- Log Cabin, Winterview Farm, Rockbridge County, Virginia, drawn by Bruce MacDougal, 1 incomplete set (2 sheets), n.d. (Box Folder 1)
- Mason House, Guilford, Accomack County, Virginia, drawn by David Bell, George Candler, & William Daggett, Jr., 1 complete set (7 sheets), 1971 (Box Folder 1)
- Pear Valley, Star Route 628, Northampton County, Virginia, drawn by Daniel Donovan, Charles King, & Bruce MacDougal, 1 complete set (5 sheets), and 1 incomplete set (2 sheets) (Box Folder 1)
- Reid-White House, Lexington, Virginia, drawn by Arthur Crook, Daniel Donovan, & Gregory Lukmire, 1 complete set (8 sheets) and 1 incomplete set (6 sheets), 1970 (Box Folder 2)
- Ritchie House, Tappahannock, Essex County, Virginia, drawn by David Bell, George Candler, & William Daggett, Jr., 1 complete set (6 sheets) and 1 incomplete set (1 sheet) (Box Folder 2)
- Rockfish Service Station, Augusta County, Virginia, drawn by Arthur Crook, Daniel Donovan, & Gregory Lukmire, 1 complete set (6 sheets), 1970 (Box Folder 2)
- Somers' House, Jamesville, Northampton County, Virginia, drawn by David Bell, George Candler, & William Daggett, Jr., 1 complete set (14 sheets), 1971 (Box Folder 2)
- Stono, Lexington, Virginia, drawn by Arthur Crook, Daniel Donovan, & Gregory Lukmire, 1 incomplete set (10 sheets), 1970 (Box Folder 2)
- Thorn Hill, Lexington, Virginia, drawn by Benjamin Dyer& James Patrick Graham, 2 complete sets (11 sheets each), 1970 (Box Folder 3)
- Tucker Cottage, Richmond, Virginia, drawn by George Candler & William Daggett, 2 complete sets (2 sheets each) (Box Folder 3)
- Wessel's Root Cellar, Hallwood, Accomack County, Virginia, drawn by David Bell & William Daggett, Jr., 1 complete set (3 sheets), 1971 (Box Folder 3)
- Westerhouse, Church Neck, Northampton County, Virginia, drawn by Bruce MacDougal, Charles King, & Daniel Donovan, 1 complete set (3 sheets) and 1 incomplete set (1 sheet) (Box Folder 3)
- Westover, Old Town Neck, Northampton County, Virginia, drawn by Bruce MacDougal, Daniel Donovan, & Charles King, 1 complete set (7 sheets) and 1 incomplete set (3 sheets) (Box Folder 3)
- Winona, Church Neck, Northampton County, Virginia, drawn by Bruce MacDougal, Charles King, & Daniel Donovan, 1 complete set (8 sheets) and 1 incomplete set (3 sheets) (Box Folder 3)